Guide to the Cornell Divestment Movement Collection, 1983-1987
Cornell Divestment Movement Collection, 1983-1987
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Cornell divestment movement collection, 1983-1987
47-5-3515
3 cubic feet.
Legal Documents, Publications, Reports
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Reports, legal documents, memos, articles, leaflets, posters, publications, and other items, all relating to the movement for Cornell divestment in South Africa.
BIOGRAPHICAL NOTE
Barbara Ebert participated in the first divestment sit-ins at Cornell's Day Hall in April-May, 1985.
Joel S. Fetzer was born on November 13, 1965, in Jacksonville, Florida. After his father, a Naval intelligence officer, was transferred to the Pentagon in Washington DC in 1970, Fetzer spent most of his childhood in the nearby suburb of Woodbridge, Virginia. He studied abroad at the Universities of Paris (France) and Manheim (Germany), then graduated summa cum laude from Cornell University with a Bachelor of Arts in Government and English in 1988. By 1996, he had received a Master of Arts, Master of Philosophy, and Ph.D. in Political Science from Yale University. While at Yale, he was awarded the Ebert Dissertation Fellowship from the Friedrich Ebert Foundation of Bonn, Germany, and the Peace Scholar Fellowship from the United States Institute of Peace.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Much of the material was collected by Barbara Ebert. Reports, legal documents, memos, articles, leaflets, posters, publications, and other items, all relating to the movement for Cornell divestment in South Africa. Material not collected by Ebert includes slides of divestment and anti Strategic Defense Initiative (Star Wars) protests on campus taken by Joel Fetzer '88..
SUBJECTS
Names:
Ebert, Barbara.; Fetzer, Joel.; Cornell University--Students.
Subjects:
Space weapons.; Strategic Defense Initiative.; Student movements.; Students--Political activity.; Disinvestment.
Places:
United States--Foreign policy--South Africa.; South Africa--Economic conditions--1961-
INFORMATION FOR USERS
CONTAINER LIST
- CCD Banking (Box 1, Folder 1)
- CCD Funding Applications (Box 1, Folder 2)
- CCD Key Lists (Box 1, Folder 3)
- CCD Official Registration(s) (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Contact Lists (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Administration Miscellaneous (Box 1, Folder 6)
- CCD Legal Matters, 1986 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Relihan Sit-In, Oct. 30, 1986 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Trespass Counts, Oct. 8, 1986 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Fingerprinting Documentation (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Contempt of Court, Oct. 8, 1986 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Court Papers, June 27, 1985 (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Change of Attorney Papers (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Getnick, Neil V., Conflict of Interest Report, May 1978 (Box 1, Folder 14)
- South African Investment Report, Dec. 6, 1978 (Box 1, Folder 15)
- Investments Report to Board of Trustees, May 28, 1983 (Box 1, Folder 16)
- Update of 1983 Report on Cornell Investments in S. Africa (Box 1, Folder 17)
- Southern Africa Activist Memorandum, Feb. 10, 1987 (Box 1, Folder 18)
- Signed Petition, Apr. 4, 1986 (Box 1, Folder 19)
- The Crisis in Minority Faculty at Cornell, Draft (Box 1, Folder 20)
- Anti-Racism Coalition (Box 1, Folder 21)
- Divestment Legal Defense Fund Banking (Box 1, Folder 22)
- Anti-Racism Coalition, 1986 (Box 1, Folder 23)
- Cornell Radical Union (Box 1, Folder 24)
- Noam Chomsky Talk Summary, Feb. 1987 (Box 1, Folder 25)
- Free Speech Commission (Box 1, Folder 26)
- Chomsky Articles (Box 1, Folder 27)
- Education Against Oppression Presentation: China in Transition, Mar. 5, 1987 (Box 1, Folder 28)
- CCD Photographs (Box 1, Folder 29)
- Violence of Racism and Militarism Info Sheets (Box 1, Folder 30)
- S.B. Fuller's Correspondence with Babara Ebert (Box 1, Folder 31)
- Petition Forms (Box 1, Folder 32)
- Copies of South Africa: Apartheid, Divestment, and Cornell (Box 1, Folder 33)
- Printouts of CCD's Computer Bulletin (Box 1, Folder 34)
- Faculty Letter to COrnell Vice President (Box 1, Folder 35)
- Faculty Network Against Apartheid, May 20, 1985 (Box 1, Folder 36)
- Peace and Justice Course Catalog, Fall 1986 (Box 1, Folder 37)
- Cornell University Commencement Brochure, May 31, 1987 (Box 1, Folder 38)
- Unions and Activities Memorandums, Aug.-Sep. 1985 (Box 1, Folder 39)
- Press Releases, June 1985-Mar. 1986 (Box 1, Folder 40)
- City of London Anti-Apartheid Group Info (Box 1, Folder 41)
- 'Divest Now' Mortarboard Covers (Box 1, Folder 42)
- Divestment Convocation Flyers and Brochures, 1985 (Box 1, Folder 43)
- Herbster Negotiations (Box 1, Folder 44)
- Miscellaneous (Box 1, Folder 45)
- South African Freedom Charter (Box 1, Folder 46)
- Activist Info Sheets and Flyers (Box 1, Folder 47-51)
- Centre Against Apartheid Notes and Documents (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Issues of Uprising! (Box 2, Folder 2)
- Issues of Sechaba (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Publications (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Pamphlets (Box 2, Folder 5)
- Issues of Outrage (Box 2, Folder 6)
- Issues of Spark (Box 2, Folder 7)
- ECSA (Box 2, Folder 8)
- Composition Journal, various authors (Box 2, Folder 9)
- National Student Conference on S. Africa Info (Box 2, Folder 10)
- Copy of Compendium of NY Law, 1975 (Box 2, Folder 11)
- Action Alerts, Articles, Miscellaneous (Box 2, Folder 12-14)
- Coalition Newspaper Clippings, 1986-1990 (Box 2, Folder 15-19)
- Newspaper Clippings (Box 2, Folder 20-23)
- Protest Artifacts (Box 3)
- Photos, Camera Film, Memorabilia (Box 4)
- Slides of divestment and anti Star Wars protests, Spring 1985 (Box 4)
  Images from the campus store, arts quad, and Day Hall. Slides taken by Joel S. Fetzer '88
- Demonstration Banners (Box 5)
- Additional items (Folder MSS Box #41)
- Oversize items (Mapcase-folder 1)